Inventory of the Richard De Rochemont papers, 1900-1997
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
- Series IV. Films, 1936-1972
  - Sub-series 4. Informational and other, 1952-1972, undated
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Garbage Bags"/"Way to Keep the City Clean" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Giant Unloader Unveiled" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 72)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "High School" (color original rolls), undated (Box 40)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "High School" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Hong Kong"/"Huge Housing Development" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 68)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Lubrication"/"Servicing the World's Newest Jets" (color), undated (Box 25)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Lubrication"/"Servicing the World's Newest Jets" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 68)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Luminescence" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 68)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Mobil Repair Center" (color), undated (Box 24)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Mobil Repair Center" (color), undated (Box 71)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Moon-Bound Atom Smasher" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Moon Lab"/"Apollo 11 News release" (color), undated (Box 33)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Moon Lab"/"Apollo 11 News release" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "North Sea"/"New Off-Shore Gas Discovery" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "PA Trash"/"Bag Your Trash Week" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Pisqui" (color), undated (Box 25)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Pisqui" (color), undated (Box 29)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Pisqui" (color), undated (Box 113)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Pisqui, part 1" (color original rolls), undated (Box 39)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Pisqui" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 61)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Pisqui" - Spanish short version (color inter-negative), undated (Box 114-115)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Science Award for Air Pollution Control" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Stat[?]" (color original rolls), undated (Box 41)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Station Award"/"Mrs. Nixon Presents Award" (color original rolls), undated (Box 145)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Statve" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Diesel Fuel Improved" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Mobil Oil Corporation - "Watts"/"Action Program in Watts" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - Montici - "Intarsia" (color), 1958 (Box 23)
    - Montici - "Intarsia" (color), undated (Box 28)
    - Montici - "Intarsia" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 12)
    - Montici - "Intarsia" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 63)
    - Montici - "Intarsia" (sound), undated (Box 78)
    - Morocco (color inter-negative), undated (Box 65)
    - Morocco (color original rolls), undated (Box 39)
    - Morocco (sound), undated (Box 116)
    - Morocco - cuts, trims, and outs (color), undated (Box 54)
    - Morocco coastline (color inter-negative), undated (Box 65)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "700 Miles of Beaches" (b&w), 1957 (Box 4)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Casbahs of the South" (b&w), 1957 (Box 4)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Casbahs of the South" (color), undated (Box 21)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Casbahs of the South" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 14)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Casbahs of the South" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 68)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Friday In Rabat" (b&w), 1957 (Box 4)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Friday In Rabat" (color), 1957 (Box 20)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Friday In Rabat" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 11)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Friday In Rabat" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 72)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Mohammed V" (b&w), undated (Box 2)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Mohammed V" (b&w), undated (Box 7)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Mysteries of Islam" (color), 1957 (Box 20)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Mysteries of Islam" (color), undated (Box 71)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Mysteries of Islam" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 14)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Mysteries of Islam" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 68)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Mysteries of Islam" (sound), undated (Box 2)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Mysteries of Islam"/"Casbahs of the South" (color), undated (Box 31)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Sporting Vacation" (b&w), 1957 (Box 4)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Sporting Vacations" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 14)
    - Moroccan Ministry of Tourism - "Sporting Vacation" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 67)
    - "Motoring" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 14)
    - "Museum In Action" (color), undated (Box 23)
    - N.A.A.C.P. (color original rolls), undated (Box 38)
    - N.A.A.C.P. (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - N.A.A.C.P. (sound), undated (Box 80)
    - N.A.A.C.P. - "Once Upon A Time" (color), undated (Box 31)
    - N.A.A.C.P. - "Once Upon a Time" (color), undated (Box 27)
    - National Homes Corporation - "Astrohome" (color), undated (Box 27)
    - National Homes Corporation - "Astrohome" (color), undated (Box 33)
    - National Homes Corporation - "Astrohome" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 66)
    - National Homes Corporation - "Astrohome" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 70)
    - National Homes Corporation - "Astrohome" (sound), undated (Box 80)
    - National Homes Corporation - "Clearwater" (color original rolls), undated (Box 126)
    - National Homes Corporation - "Swedish Film", undated (Box 127-128)
    - Navy training film, undated (Box 209)
    - "NH Ytong" (color), undated (Box 27)
    - "NH-Ytong" (sound), undated (Box 73)
    - "Normandy" (color), undated (Box 129)
    - "Normandy" (color original rolls), undated (Box 41)
    - "Oldest Paris" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 70)
    - Omnibus - "Invitation to Harvard" (b&w), undated (Box 5)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 13)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln (sound), undated (Box 74)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - Episode 1 - "End of the Beginning" (b&w), undated (Box 5)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - Episode 1 - "End of the Beginning", undated (Box 117)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - Episode 2 - "Nancy Hanks", undated (Box 118)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - Episode 3 - "Growing Up", undated (Box 119)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - Episode 4 - "New Salem", undated (Box 120)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - Episode 5 - "Ann Rutledge", undated (Box 121)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - reel 1 (inter-negative), undated (Box 122)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - reel 1 (sound), undated (Box 123)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - reel 3 (inter-negative), undated (Box 124)
    - Omnibus - Mr. Lincoln - reel 3 (sound), undated (Box 125)
    - Omnibus - "Robert Frost" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 14)
    - Omnibus - "Robert Frost" (b&w), undated (Box 16)
    - Omnibus - "Robert Frost" (b&w), undated (Box 4)
    - Omnibus - "Robert Frost" (b&w), undated (Box 6)
    - Omnibus - "Robert Frost" (sound), undated (Box 75)
    - Omnibus - "Winter in the French Alps" (color), undated (Box 26)
    - Overseas Press Club (b&w), 1958 (Box 9)
    - Overseas Press Club awards dinner (b&w), 1952 (Box 5)
    - Overseas Press Club awards dinner (b&w), 1959 (Box 4)
    - Oyster Bay - "Town of Oyster Bay Story" (color original rolls), undated (Box 38)
    - Oyster Bay - "Town of Oyster Bay Story" (sound), undated (Box 80)
    - "Paint Your Wagon" (color), 1969 (Box 25)
    - Parade Publications, Inc. - "Young Columbus XV Iberian Adventure" (color), undated (Box 28)
    - Parade Publications, Inc. - "Young Columbus XVI Greece-Switzerland Adventure" (color), undated (Box 22)
    - "Paradise Street" (color), undated (Box 130)
    - "Peter Burton In Paris" - outs, trims, and cuts (color), undated (Box 55)
    - "PF-149" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 131)
    - Reynold's Metals Company - "Closed Circuit TV Show,", undated (Box 213)
    - Reynold's Metals Company - "Aluminum In Modern Architecture" (b&w), circa 1956 (Box 7)
    - Richard De Rochemont at dinner, undated (Box 207)
    - "R.O.P. Color" (color), 1959 (Box 144)
    - Roquefort Association - "Treat For the Gods" (color), undated (Box 30)
    - "Save the Children" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 13)
    - "Sea Venture" (color), undated (Box 71)
    - Seventeen Magazine - "Age of Curiosity" (color), undated (Box 24)
    - Seventeen Magazine - "Age of Curiosity" (color), undated (Box 26)
    - Seventeen Magazine - "Age of Curiosity" (color original rolls), undated (Box 38)
    - Seventeen Magazine - "Age of Curiosity" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 13)
    - Seventeen Magazine - "Age of Curiosity" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 67)
    - Seventeen Magazine - "Age of Curiosity" (sound), undated (Box 80)
    - Sheraton - Reynolds (b&w), 1956 (Box 16)
    - Simon & Schuster - "Almanac" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 66)
    - Standard Oil Company (color original rolls), undated (Box 39)
    - Standard Oil Company (New Jersey) - "Quality Of Life" (color), undated (Box 32)
    - Standard Oil Company (New Jersey) - "Through the Northwest Passage" (color), undated (Box 139)
    - Standard Oil Company (New Jersey) - "Through the Northwest Passage" (color), undated (Box 146-148)
    - Standard Oil Company (New Jersey) - "Tomorrow's Scientists & Engineers" (color), undated (Box 24)
    - "Televiewer" (color original rolls), undated (Box 58)
    - "Theatre of Etienne Decroux" (b&w), undated (Box 9)
    - "Theatre of Etienne Decroux" (b&w), undated (Box 149-150)
    - "They're Taking the Bus In Nashville" (sound), 1959 September (Box 2)
    - Time - "Time's Man of the Year" (color), undated (Box 151)
    - "Together Eleven" (color), undated (Box 28)
    - "Town of Oyster Bay" (color), 1963 (Box 22)
    - "Town of Oyster Bay" (color), undated (Box 31)
    - "Treat For the Gods" (color), undated (Box 23)
    - "Tropical Island" (sound), undated (Box 78)
    - TWA - "Twin Air" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 69)
    - "Type to Paper" (color), undated (Box 152)
    - Unidentified (nitrate film), undated (Box 211)
    - Unidentified (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 81)
    - Unidentified (sound), undated (Box 80)
    - United States Line Company - "Superliner United States At Your Service!" (b&w), undated (Box 4)
    - "Upjohn Display" (color inter-negative), undated (Box 67)
    - "UpJohn Display" (color original rolls), undated (Box 41)
    - VD (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 81)
    - "Versailles" (color), undated (Box 30)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (b&w), 1961 (Box 2)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (b&w), undated (Box 2)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (color original rolls), undated (Box 38)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (color inter-negative), undated (Box 66)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (sound), undated (Box 153)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - "25th Birthday Celebration" (b&w), undated (Box 2)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - "Museum In Action" (color), undated (Box 31)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - "Silver Rally" (b&w), undated (Box 2)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - "Sport and the Horse" (b&w), undated (Box 2)
    - War on the Seas, undated (Box 208)
    - "When I'm Old Enough Goodbye" (b&w), undated (Box 6)
    - "When I'm Old Enough Goodbye" (b&w), undated (Box 8)
    - "When I'm Old Enough Goodbye" (b&w), undated (Box 9)
    - "When I'm Old Enough Goodbye" (b&w inter-negative), undated (Box 15)
    - "When I'm Old Enough Goodbye" (sound), undated (Box 73-74)
    - "World Assembly Of Youth" (b&w), undated (Box 9)
- Series V. Photographs, circa 1916-1969, undated
  Arranged alphabetically. Contains photographs created during the production of De Rochemont films (including the March of Time newsreels), as well as personal and family photographs of De Rochemont. Series includes prints, color slides, and negatives.
  - American Chamber of Commerce in France dinner, 1945 (Box 205)
  - ANTA salute to France dinner, 1955 (Box 205)
  - Baker, Josephine, undated (Box 201)
  - Basque country (color slides ), undated (Box 203)
  - Booth, Claire, undated (Box 201)
  - Captain Cook, undated (Box 201)
  - Clofines At Long Island Home, undated (Box 200)
  - Corsica? (color slides), undated (Box 204)
  - De Grelle, Leon, undated (Box 201)
  - De Gaulle, Charles and De Rochemont (negatives), 1945 (Box 201)
  - De Rochemont family, undated (Box 201)
  - De Rochemont family residences, undated (Box 201)
  - De Rochemont home, circa 1916-1925 (Box 205)
  - De Rochemont, Richard, undated (Box 201)
  - De Rochemont, Richard, 1945-1951 (Box 205)
  - De Rochemont, Richard (negatives), undated (Box 201)
  - De Rochemont, Richard and family, 1900-1997 (Box 216)
  - De Villemoran, William and Betty, undated (Box 201)
  - Dinner (French), 1948, 1951 (Box 205)
  - Dinner in honor of Henri Bonnet, Ambassador of France, 1955 (Box 205)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., undated (Box 201)
  - Eglin Air Base (color slides), undated (Box 204)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica Films, Inc. - first board of directors meeting, 1944 (Box 205)
  - English in Cannes, undated (Box 200)
  - European town views, undated (Box 200)
  - Fifth Annual Nobel Anniversary dinner, 1945 (Box 205)
  - Final Eisenhower "crusade" commercial (nitrate negatives), 1949 (Box 214)
  - Flemington, New Jersey - old and new houses (color slides), undated (Box 204)
  - Flemington, New Jersey - old and new houses (negatives), circa 1962-1964 (Box 201)
  - France, undated (Box 200)
  - France, undated (Box 205)
  - France (color slides), 1956-1962 (Box 204)
  - France (nitrate negatives), undated (Box 214)
  - France - Clofines in France, undated (Box 200)
  - France - Gandhi, 1933 (Box 201)
  - France - industry and agriculture (from album), undated (Box 200)
  - France - Paris, circa 1945 (Box 200)
  - France - Riviera and Red Cross (photographs by Marcel Rebiere), 1941 (Box 200)
  - France - Vichy and Red Cross (photographs by Marcel Rebiere) (nitrate negatives), 1941 (Box 214)
  - France - Vichy (Bistro interior shots), circa 1945 (Box 200)
  - French American Club dinner, 1943 (Box 205)
  - Frost, Robert and Bela Horwitzer, undated (Box 201)
  - Gorki, Maxime, undated (Box 201)
  - Houston Museum (color slides), 1963 (Box 203)
  - Hungary, undated (Box 200)
  - Italy, undated (Box 201)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1963 (Box 201)
  - Josephine Baker - "An American in France" (nitrate negatives), undated (Box 214)
  - Luce, Henry, undated (Box 201)
  - Luce, Henry, undated (Box 205)
  - Luce, Henry and De Rochemont (negatives), 1941 (Box 201)
  - March of Time, undated (Box 200)
  - March of Time, undated (Box 205)
  - March of Time (nitrate negatives), undated (Box 214)
  - March of Time - black market, undated (Box 200)
  - March of Time - Czechoslovakia and Hungary, undated (Box 200)
  - March of Time - filming (photographs by Marcel Rebiere), undated (Box 200)
  - March of Time - Germany, WWII, undated (Box 200)
  - March of Time - "Golden Twenties", undated (Box 200)
  - March of Time - Prague, undated (Box 200)
  - March of Time - Testevin ceremonies, New York, undated (Box 201)
  - March of Time - "Wartime" episodes (filming in France, Italy, and Berlin), circa 1944 (Box 200)
  - March of Time - World Assembly of Youth, Ithaca, New York, 1951 (Box 200)
  - March of Time - WWII, undated (Box 200)
  - Mexico (color slides), 1962-1963 (Box 203)
  - Mexio and Oyster Bay, undated (Box 200)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 201)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 205)
  - Miscellaneous (color slides), undated (Box 203)
  - Mother of De Rochemont (nitrate negatives), undated (Box 214)
  - Motorama, 1956 (Box 201)
  - Moulin de [?], Pontlevoy, France (nitrate negatives), undated (Box 214)
  - "Mr. Lincoln", undated (Box 201)
  - News Photographers' Association Annual White House Dinner with President Truman, 1945 (Box 205)
  - Olmec Head (color slides), 1962-1963 (Box 203)
  - Pages, Jean, undated (Box 201)
  - Personal and unidentified, undated (Box 201)
  - Peru - Cuzco and Pisac (color slides), 1965 (Box 203)
  - Pontlevoy, undated (Box 201)
  - Pontlevoy (color slides), 1961 (Box 204)
  - Pretender to the throne of the Ukraine, circa 1935-1937 (Box 201)
  - Reed, Waverly, undated (Box 201)
  - Reynold's Metals Company - closed circuit, 1956 (Box 201)
  - Richard De Rochemont in Paris (color slides), 1939 (Box 203)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, undated (Box 201)
  - Spain - Barcelona, undated (Box 200)
  - Testevin chapitre (color slides), 1963 (Box 202)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 200)
  - Unidentified (color slides), undated (Box 202)
  - Unidentified (glass plate negatives), undated (Box 201)
  - Unidentified (nitrate negatives), undated (Box 214)
  - Visit of Jimmy Sanger to Flemington (color slides), 1964 (Box 203)
  - Williams College Class of 1924, 1969 (Box 205)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, undated (Box 201)
  - Wright Field, General Wray, et. al. (color slides), undated (Box 204)
  - Zarahoff, (Sir) Basil, undated (Box 201)
- Series VI. Audio, 1956-1969, undated
  Arranged alphabetically. Contains reel-to-reel audio tapes, including sound for some of De Rochemont’s films, and four phonograph records. All are reel-to-reel unless otherwise labeled.
  - "Air France Jets", 1961 (Box 82)
  - "Chateau", 1956 (Box 82)
  - Dashaies, Guadeloupe - Fort Royal Hotel, undated (Box 82)
  - Dean Brelis reports from Cyprus, undated (Box 83)
  - "Decroux", 1961 (Box 83)
  - Dr. Raymond Fielding on "The March of Time" (cassette), undated (Box 82)
  - Edward R. Murrow, undated (Box 83)
  - "French Caribbean", 1965 (Box 82)
  - "French Motoring", 1956 (Box 82)
  - Gaude Maria; Societe d'Autrefois Vocal Ensemble under the direction of Yvonne Gouverne, undated (Box 83)
  - "Houston Museum", 1964 (Box 83)
  - Hurard Coppet - "Pres de la Riviere", 1965 (Box 82)
  - "In the Peaceful Valley Of Loire", 1958 (Box 82)
  - Marshall [?] interview, 1966 (Box 82)
  - McLuhan [?] with Eric Goldman, undated (Box 82)
  - MEWS, 1958 (Box 83)
  - "Montici" and "The Oldest Paris", 1958 (Box 82)
  - Of bird [?], 1967 (Box 82)
  - "Oyster Bay", 1963 (Box 83)
  - Radio tributes to George Clay - Merrill Mueller, Chet Huntley, Monitor, undated (Box 83)
  - Sheehan report from London - ABC, 1964 October 11 (Box 83)
  - Southern Paris, undated (Box 82)
  - "Symphonie Fantastique", undated (Box 83)
  - Unidentified [3], 1969 (Box 82)
  - Unidentified [3], undated (Box 82)
  - Unidentified, 1956 (Box 82)
  - "Virginia Museum", 1961 (Box 83)
  - Phonograph record - Department of State - "Reporters at Work", 1949 [1940?] (Box 212)
  - Phonograph record - March of Time Ithaca story music - "Afternoon of a Faun" by Debussy, 1951 (Box 212)
  - Phonograph record - WOR reference record - "Black Market" (broken), 1943 (Box 212)
  - Phonograph record - WOR reference record - "Don't Let's Be Beastly to the Germans", 1944 (Box 212)